(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
皆さん、こんにちは！ときのそらです。
Hello everyone! I'm Tokino Sora.
本日は『HappyMeowthday!!』3Dライブ、
Today is the 'HappyMeowthday!!' 3D live,
見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
thank you so much for coming to see it!
気まぐれメルシィ feat. 初音ミク
Kimagure Mercy feat. Hatsune Miku
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
お得意の自己弁護言い訳
Your specialty: self-defense and excuses
でもね　だって
But you know, "because..."
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
ごめんからのキスのパターンって感じ
The "kiss after apologizing" pattern
あーにー
Ah, hey...
いつか私だけ　そんな夢見たこともあったけど
I once dreamed of being the only one for you
寂しい時だけ電話して　もううんざりだわ
Calling only when you're lonely, I'm sick of it
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You have no interest in me at all
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The one you love is yourself, isn't it?
Yeah やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Yeah, I knew it, you're not interested in me
その話も聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story
そもそもだいたい私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
そうやってまたごまかしても
Even if you try to deceive me like that again
Be my boy　わがまま過ぎるベイベー
Be my boy, you're too selfish, baby
抱きしめてよね
Hold me tight, okay?
ほんときみはしょうもないな
You really are hopeless
まあ私もしょうがないな
Well, I guess I'm helpless too
泣いたって行かないでって言ったって
Even if I cry or tell you not to go,
食わぬのよ
it won't work
もう少しだけならまあ踊ってもいいかもな
Maybe it's okay to dance just a little longer
蕩けて解けていきたいの
I want to melt and dissolve away
どんなアピールも意味ないし
No matter how I appeal to you, it's meaningless
気づいてくれないけど
You don't even notice
私が寂しい時だって
Even when I'm feeling lonely,
会いに来て
come and see me
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You have no interest in me at all
どこがダメなのか教えてよ
Tell me what's wrong with me
Yeah やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Yeah, I knew it, you're not interested in me
携帯ばかりいじってさ
You're always playing with your phone
そもそもだいたい私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
少しぐらい期待させてよ
Let me have a little bit of hope
Lonely girl　独り占めてよベイベー
Lonely girl, keep me all to yourself, baby
振り向かせないで
Don't make me look away
Hey baby melty one-two-step with me
踊りましょう
Let's dance
速くて　蕩けて　繋いで
Fast, melting, and connecting
最後に一つだけ
One last thing
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me so much I feel like I'm drowning
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You have no interest in me at all
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The one you love is yourself, isn't it?
Yeah やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Yeah, I knew it, you're not interested in me
その話も聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story
そもそもだいたい私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
そうやってまたごまかしても
Even if you try to deceive me like that again
Get it up!　覚悟はできてるの
Get it up! I'm prepared for this
きまぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
はい！ということで始まりました！
Yes! And so it has begun!
お誕生日ライブ！
My Birthday Live!
1曲目から振り付けありの曲を踊ってみました！
I tried dancing a song with choreography
right from the very first song!
どうでしたでしょうか！
How was it?!
本日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming today!
そらちあ！パチパチありがとうございます！
Sora-chi! Thank you for the applause!
たくさんの人に見てもらえてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy so many people are watching!
ちょっと喉が渇きましたね。
My throat's gotten a bit dry.
飲み物飲んできますね。
I'm going to get something to drink.
はい。美味しいお水でした。
Okay. That was delicious water.
というわけで今回はバースデーライブなんですが、
So, this is a birthday live,
いろんなダンスをね、踊ったり踊ったりしていきたいなと思っておりますので、
and I'm planning on dancing all sorts
of different dances,
ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
so please look forward to it!
そしてね、また途中には、お披露目もございますので、
And also, there will be a reveal later on,
楽しんでいって頂けたら嬉しいなと思います！
so I hope you enjoy it to the end!
やったー！
Yay!
お水あいてくる...
I'll go get some water...
はい。お水は美味しかったよ。
Okay. The water was delicious.
というわけでね、早速1人目のゲスト、
And so, without further ado, our first guest...
呼んじゃおうかな！
I'll go ahead and call them out!
ルイちゃーーん！
Lui-chaaan!
はーい！そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Hi! Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとーー！
Thank you!!
そして、この場に、来れて本当に光栄です、ありがとうございますお誘い頂きまして。
And I'm truly honored to be here.
Thank you so much for inviting me.
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます。
No, thank you for coming.
ところで。
By the way...
なんて呼べばいいですか？
What should I call you?
おお、うわぁ。実は、だってそうですよね。
Oh, wow. Actually, that's right.
そう。まだ喋ってなかったですもんね。
Right. We haven't talked about that yet.
え、なんて呼んでもらおう... なんて呼べばいい？
Hmm, what should I have you call me...?
Wait, what should I call you?
ちょっと、ルイるいって呼んでもらってもいいですか？
Could you call me 'Lui-rui'?
えっ、ルイるい？！呼びたかったやつだ！
Eh, Lui-rui?! That's what I wanted to call you!
ええ、嬉しい！
Yay, I'm so happy!
じゃあ今日から、私はルイるい... 私はルイるいじゃない。
Then starting today, I'm Lui-rui...
Wait, I'm not Lui-rui.
あ、そこ、ルイるいになっちゃった。
Ah, you became Lui-rui there.
ふふ、ルイるいって呼びますね。
Hehe, I'll call you Lui-rui then.
お願いします。嬉しい！
Please do. I'm happy!
ねー、本当に嬉しい. なんかね、ずっとお歌がすごい上手で、
Yeah, I'm really happy. You know, your singing
has always been so good,
なんかね、よく聞いてたから、一緒にね、歌いたいなって思ってたの。
and I listened to it often, so I've been
wanting to sing with you.
もう本当に光栄です、もう本当に。鳥肌立ってる、今。
I'm truly honored, really.
I have goosebumps right now.
ありがとー。いや、こちらこそありがとう。
Thank you. No, thank you as well.
今日一緒に歌えるの、本当に楽しみで、昨日夜眠れなくて。
I was really looking forward to singing together
today, I couldn't sleep last night.
ちょっともう本当に緊張してるんですけど。
I'm really quite nervous.
でもさっきめちゃくちゃご飯めっちゃ食べてたよね。
But you were eating a ton of food just a bit ago.
確かに、緊張するとご飯も喉を通らないっていうわけではないんです。
True, it's not like food won't go down my throat
just because I'm nervous.
ない。普通に食べてた。
Nope. You were eating normally.
食べてました。パクパクと。
I was. Munching away.
美味しそうと思って見てた。
I was watching you, thinking it looked tasty.
そら先輩は緊張してたから、食べれなかったですか？
Were you unable to eat, Sora-senpai,
because you were nervous?
あ、緊張するとね、なんかね、テンションが上がっちゃって、
Ah, when I'm nervous, you know,
my energy goes way up,
あ、そわそわってなって、なんかあんまり何て言うんだろう。
and I get all fidgety, and I can't really...
how should I say it?
いや、そわそわしてるそら先輩も、ちょっと間近で見て可愛いなって思ってました。
Well, seeing Sora-senpai being fidgety up close,
I thought you were cute.
本当？ありがと！
Really? Thank you!
さあ、そんなルイるいちゃんとね、ライブしたいんですけど、
Now then, I want to perform with Lui-rui, but...
その前に、ちょっとね、なんか付けちゃおうかなーって思っております。
before that, I think I'll put something on.
お、じゃあ付けちゃいます？
Oh, so you're going to put it on?
付けちゃいます。
I'm putting it on.
じゃあ私で一旦隠して...
Then I'll hide you for a bit...
にゃー！
Meow!
猫しっぽもあるよ。
I have a cat tail too.
お、本当だ！あれ、なくなってる？
Oh, it's true! Wait, is it gone?
なかった！
It wasn't there!
さっきあったのに！
It was there just now!
え、さっき、え、なんでないんだ？
Eh, just now... eh, why isn't it there?
でも、耳がめちゃくちゃ可愛いですね、キュート。
But the ears are super cute. So cute.
カチューシャは付けてます。
I'm wearing a headband.
可愛いです、可愛い。
It's cute, so cute.
これを付けるということは、こういう感じの曲なんじゃないでしょうか！
Wearing this must mean it's this kind of song!
ということで一緒に歌いましょう！
So let's sing together!
はい、ぜひぜひお願いします！
Yes, by all means!
お願いします。それでは聴いてください。
Please. Now, please listen.
鳴呼、素晴らしきニャン生。
Ah, It's a Wonderful Cat's Life.
鳴呼、素晴らしきニャン生
作詞・作曲：Nem
Ah, It's a Wonderful Cat's Life
Lyrics/Composition: Nem
これは可愛いお嬢さん
Well, what a cute young lady
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
That pure white fur is very lovely
こんな月が綺麗な夜は
On a night when the moon is this beautiful,
僕と一緒に遊びませんか
won't you come and play with me?
ニャン生は一度きり
You only live a cat's life once,
楽しむが勝ちなのです
so whoever has the most fun wins.
あなたを縛る首輪は
That collar that binds you,
噛みちぎってあげましょう
let me bite it off for you.
野良は最高　ニャンニャンニャン
Being a stray is the best, nyan nyan nyan,
魚くすねて　鳩追いかけて
stealing fish, chasing pigeons.
昼間は働く人間を　尻目に屋根の上で夢をむさぼる
While humans work during the day,
we indulge in dreams on the rooftops.
あなたも自由に　ニャンニャンニャン
You can be free too, nyan nyan nyan.
素敵な仲間も紹介しましょう
I'll introduce you to some wonderful friends.
その窓を開いて
Open that window
飛び出すので
I'm jumping out
これは気ままな野良猫さん 闇の中目だけが光ってる
This is a carefree stray cat, with eyes shining in the dark
随分口が上手だけど 私は馬鹿な女じゃないわ
You're quite the smooth talker, but I'm no fool
ニャン生は一度きり
A cat's life is only once
だからこそ飼われるのよ
That's why I'm kept
ブランド首輪の価値が あなたにはわかるかしら
Do you understand the value of a brand collar?
私は優雅なニャンニャンニャン 美味しい食事にふかふかベッド
I'm an elegant nyan nyan nyan, with delicious food and a soft bed
水はちょっぴり苦手だけど 毎日シャワーだって浴びれるの
I'm a bit bad with water, but I can take a shower every day
これに比べてニャンニャンニャン あなたは誰に守ってもらうの
Compared to this, nyan nyan nyan, who is going to protect you?
明日車に轢かれるかも しれないじゃない
You might get hit by a car tomorrow, you know
そんな強気なとこも素敵です いっそあなたを
That confident side of yours is wonderful too. I'd rather...
好きになりました
...fall in love with you.
あら正直ね でもそんなやり方じゃ 心揺れないわ
Oh, how honest. But that way won't sway my heart.
僕の夢はニャンニャンニャン いつかはこの街を飛び出して
My dream is nyan nyan nyan, to one day jump out of this town
はるか北の国に旅して オーロラをこの目で見ること
Travel to a far northern country and see the aurora with my own eyes
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン いてくれたらなんて素敵でしょう
If you were there with me, nyan nyan nyan, how wonderful that would be
だけどそれは叶わないらしい
But it seems that won't come true
生き方はニャンニャンニャン そう簡単には変えられないの
A way of life, nyan nyan nyan, can't be changed that easily
それに私を飼っている 女の子一人にできないわ
And I can't leave the girl who's keeping me all alone
話の途中よ ニャンニャンニャン あらもう行っちゃうのねちょっと
I'm in the middle of talking, nyan nyan nyan, oh you're leaving already, wait
明日もここに来ていいのよ 待ってるから
You can come here tomorrow too, I'll be waiting
そら先輩お誕生日本当におめでとうございます
Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
この後も楽しみにしてるので、頑張ってください！
I'm looking forward to what's next, so please do your best!
頑張るよ！ルイ！
I will! Lui!
ルイちゃんありがとう！
Thank you, Lui-chan!
はぁ、というわけで「嗚呼、素晴らしきニャン生」をルイちゃんと歌いました！
Phew, so I sang "Ah, It's a Wonderful Cat Life" with Lui-chan!
いやね、ハモリがすごい難しくって、ルイちゃんとね、大事にね、練習もしたんですけど
The harmony was really difficult, so I practiced hard with Lui-chan.
やらなんか、ね、本番でこんな感じでできると思ってなかったので
But I didn't think we'd be able to do it like this in the actual performance.
なんか、あれ？尻尾ある？あれ？
Wait, is there a tail? Huh?
あれ？
Huh?
なんか、いやちょっと緊張がちょっとほぐれましたね
Well, my nervousness has eased up a bit.
まだまだ緊張する曲だらけなんですけども
I still have plenty of songs left that make me nervous, though.
ね、ルイちゃんがすごいいい、ね、素敵な低音ボイスで
Lui-chan has such a wonderful, lovely low voice.
もう私ね、この曲をね、提案してくれたのルイちゃんなんですよ
Actually, it was Lui-chan who suggested this song to me.
こういうこの、デュエットの曲でどうですか？って言われて
She asked me, "How about this duet song?"
「ぜひぜひ！ぜひぜひ！」って言ってやった曲だったので
And I said, "By all means! Please!" so that's how we ended up doing it.
すごいなんか、一緒に歌えて嬉しかったし
I was really happy to sing it together.
ね！ちゃんとここで二人でこう、フォーメーションをとってできたのがとっても嬉しかったです
And! I was very happy that the two of us were able to do the formation here properly.
ルイちゃん、本当にありがとう！
Lui-chan, thank you so much!
そしてそして、次の曲なんですけども
And now, for the next song...
次の曲は新曲になっております！
The next song is a new song!
ま、今日ね、受注生産で届いた人がいっぱいいると思うんですけど
I think many people received it today through made-to-order.
「Happy Meowthday!!」っていう曲です。これですね。
It's a song called "Happy Meowthday!!". This one.
これなんですけど、もうあの受注終わっちゃってるんですけど
As for this, the orders have already closed, but...
今度、いつだっけな、もうすぐ、えっと、配信が
Next, when was it, soon, um, the digital release...
18日から配信が決まっておりますので
The digital release is set for the 18th.
曲が気になるなとか、いいなって思った人はぜひぜひチェックしてもらえると嬉しいです
If you're interested in the song or think it's good, I'd be happy if you'd check it out.
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
可愛い！可愛い！
Cute! Cute!
それではその曲を歌っていこうと思います！
Now, I'm going to sing that song!
聴いてください、「Happy Meowthday!!」
Please listen to "Happy Meowthday!!"
もふもふ抱きしめニャンニャンニャン
Fluffy hug nyan nyan nyan
そのつぶらな瞳 ずるいでしょ
Those round eyes are unfair, aren't they?
年一度の大事な記念日もキミと一緒だよ
This important anniversary once a year, I'm with you too
Even on this once-a-year important anniversary, I'm with you.
さぁ、Happy Meowthday!!
Now, Happy Meowthday!!
大変だ、大変だ、甘えん坊、始まった
Oh no, oh no, the spoiled child has begun.
そんなの、もう反則だよ。現行犯の事件だよ
That's already against the rules. It's an in-flagrante incident.
もしかして、今きっと、心通じ合ったの？
Could it be, right now, our hearts have connected?
思わせぶりな態度に揺さぶられて
Shaken by a suggestive attitude.
そんな今日、は私の大切な日
Today like this is my precious day.
いちごのショートケーキもプレゼントも
Both the strawberry shortcake and the presents...
嬉しくてたまんなくて、笑顔で頬が痛くて
I'm so happy I can't help it, my cheeks hurt from smiling.
幸せって意外と傍にあるのかな？
Is happiness unexpectedly close by?
いつも通り「大好きだ」って笑いながら
As usual, while smiling and saying "I love you."
いつも通り隣で寝転んでいたいの
I want to be lying down next to you as usual.
もふもふパーティーは始まったばかりだよ
The fluffy party has only just begun.
キミとの、Happy Birthday,
Happy Birthday with you,
つまりは、Happy Meowthday!!
In other words, Happy Meowthday!!
もうすぐ日付も変わる頃
The date will soon change.
魔法が解ける静けさの前に
Before the silence when the magic breaks.
思いふけっちゃって、なんか妙に寂しくなって
Getting lost in thought, I feel strangely lonely.
ヒトの気持ちってにゃんだか難しいな
Human feelings are somewhat difficult, aren't they?
いつも通り「大好きだ」って笑いながら
As usual, while smiling and saying "I love you."
いつも通り隣で寝転んでいたいの
I want to be lying down next to you as usual.
もふもふパーティーは終わりの時間だよ
The fluffy party is coming to an end.
さよなら、Happy Birthday,
Goodbye, Happy Birthday,
ありがと、Happy Meowthday!!
Thank you, Happy Meowthday!!
にゃっ、にゃっ
Meow, meow.
今この瞬間が思い出になって、残っていますように。
May this moment become a memory and remain.
また目を覚ました時、隣にいますように。
When I wake up again, I hope I'm next to you.
もふもふ抱きしめにゃんにゃんにゃん
Fluffy hug, meow meow meow.
その甘い鳴き声、ずるいでしょ。
That sweet cry is unfair, isn't it?
ずっとこれからもよろしくね
Let's continue to be close from now on too.
さぁ、Happy Meowthday!!
Now, Happy Meowthday!!
はい、ということで Happy Meowthday!! でした。
Yes, so that was Happy Meowthday!!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
可愛すぎる？本当に？
Too cute? Really?
ありがとう嬉しい。
Thank you, I'm happy.
ぱちぱちもありがとう。
Thank you for the clapping too.
超素晴らしい。ありがとうございます。
Super wonderful. Thank you very much.
なんかね、この動きが可愛くできるかなって、ちょっと不安だったんですけど
I was a bit worried about whether I could do these movements cutely...
可愛くできて、よかったなと思います。
...but I'm glad I could do them cutely.
みんなが可愛いと思ってくれていたら、とても嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy if everyone thinks I'm cute.
めっちゃ可愛すぎる。ありがとう。お誕生日おめでとう。ありがとう。
Extremely too cute. Thank you. Happy birthday. Thank you.
また飲み物を飲もう。
Let's drink something again.
めっちゃ可愛。ありがとう。ありがとう。
So cute. Thank you. Thank you.
はい、というわけでね。
Yes, well then.
後でまたもう一曲、新曲を歌おうと思っているので
I'm planning to sing another new song later...
最後まで見ててください。
...so please watch until the end.
というわけで、次のゲストさんのためにですね、ちょっと変身しちゃおうかなと思います。
And so, I think I'll change a bit for the next guest.
行くよー！
Here I go!
なんだと思う？何に変身すると思う？
What do you think? What do you think I'll change into?
めっちゃ飲み物飲めてえらい。そうだね。めっちゃ飲み物飲めてるけども。
Drinking so many drinks, you're so good. That's true. I am drinking a lot of drinks though.
じゃあドリンクタイムは終わったということで。じゃあ…
Well, with the drink time over, let's...
ひらけ、どん！
Open, bam!
はい。ということで、また私服です。
Yes. So, I'm back in casual wear.
でも私服でさ、ここ立つの初めてなんだけど。
But it's my first time standing here in casual wear.
なんか、この服で、ここなんか豪華だね。なんかそんな感じがしますね。
Somehow, with these clothes, it feels luxurious here. That's how it feels.
というわけで、早速この衣装でね、会いたい人を…
So, with this outfit, I'll call the person I want to see...
呼んじゃおうかなと思います。
...right now.
しらちゃーん！
Shira-chan!
あれ？この辺りに私服姿のアイドルがいるって聞いたんだけど、どこかな？
Huh? I heard there was an idol in casual wear around here, but where is she?
どこかな？どこかな？
Where? Where?
はっ、はっ、あそこにいるのは！
Ah! Ah! The person over there is!
ももいろそらちゃん！
Pink Sora-chan!
ひえー！さっきから見てて、こんな桃色の姿できてくれるなんて！
Hieee! I was watching, and for you to come out in pink like this!
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
本当に、そらともさん、そして…
Really, the Soratomo, and...
えっ、ときのそらちゃん！
Eh, Sora-chan!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
シロちゃんのそのお洋服かわいいんだけど
Siro-chan, those clothes are so cute!
あははは、もう、
Ahahaha, well,
いっぱい、いっぱいそらちゃんの活動を見てきたから、
I've watched so many of Sora-chan's activities,
今日を迎えられて本当によかったね。
so I'm really glad we could reach today.
本当に嬉しい。
I'm truly happy.
あ、本当に嬉しい。
Ah, I'm really happy.
そして私、シロちゃんとずっと一緒に
And I've always wanted to...
同じステージに立って歌いたくて、
...stand and sing on the same stage with Siro-chan.
あ、エモい、エモすぎる。
Oh, it's so emotional, too emotional.
だからその夢を叶えたくて、今日呼んだんだよね。
That's why I called you today, to make that dream come true.
来てくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming.
こちらこそだよ！
The pleasure is all mine!
シロも、あのそらちゃんの歌が大好きで
Siro loves Sora-chan's singing too.
本当に？
Really?
本当にアイドルとして憧れてるので、
I truly admire you as an idol,
歌いたいって思ってたから、めっちゃ嬉しい。
so I've wanted to sing with you. I'm so happy.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
せ、せっかくなので、シロができる何かことで、
S-S-Since we're here, is there anything I can do,
リクエストあったりしますか？
any requests?
え、私なんか、
Eh, for me, well,
本当に私だけが得しちゃうんですけど、
I'm the only one who really benefits from this, but...
ギュッと抱きしめて...
...give me a big hug...
ご褒美ですか！？
Is this a reward!?
いいんですか！？
Is it okay!?
あ、失礼します！
Ah, excuse me!
わあ！
Wow!
いい匂いする...
You smell good...
そらちゃん本当によく頑張ったね。
Sora-chan, you've really worked hard, haven't you?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
これからもずっとずっとアイドルの姿見せてね。
Please keep showing us your idol self forever.
シロ...！
Siro...!
私ずっと先輩としてなんか、
I've always looked up to you as my senior,
シロちゃんのことを追いかけてきてたので、
and have been following you,
今一緒にこうやってステージに立てるのが
so being able to stand on stage together like this
本当に幸せです。ありがとうございます。
makes me really happy. Thank you very much.
こちらこそ！
The pleasure is all mine!
シロも、なんか色んな曇りの日も雨の日も、
Siro also, on cloudy days and rainy days,
そらちゃんの歌を聴いたりして
I'd listen to Sora-chan's songs
勝手に応援したり、
and cheer you on in my own way.
なんかそらちゃんは本当に最初は
You know, Sora-chan, at first...
バブみとかママみがあるっていうので
people were talking about your 'baby-like' or 'motherly' vibes,
そらちゃんに出会った時期もあったんですけど...
and that's when I first encountered you.
なんだろう、本当に一歩一歩、
But you know, step by step,
そらともさんと手を繋ぎながら、
while holding hands with the Soratomos,
シロも後ろからついてきてたんで、
Siro was also following from behind.
自分の道を進んでいて本当にキラキラしてて、
Moving forward on your own path, you're truly sparkling,
かっこいいです！
and so cool!
嬉しいありがとう！
I'm so happy, thank you!
こちらこそだよ！
Likewise!
今日もね、リハーサルでいっぱいいっぱい
I know you've been practicing so hard in rehearsals today
そらともさんを喜ばせようと思って練習してたの知ってるの！
to make the Soratomos happy!
ありがとう、なんか恥ずかしいんだけど。
Thank you, it's a bit embarrassing.
あ、じゃあ、もっとちゃんと歌ったり、
Ah, then, I'll sing even better,
シロはアイドルなんだから！
since Siro is an idol too!
わかったよ！
I got it!
ちゃんと練習します！
I'll practice properly!
あ、違う違う、もっと今日、あの、他の歌も聞けたら...
Ah, no no, I meant if I could hear other songs today...
そういうこと！？
Is that it!?
なんか、漫才をしたいのかとちょっと...
I thought for a second you wanted to do a comedy skit...
あ、漫才しますか？
Oh, shall we do a skit?
どうも、電脳少女シロです！
Hello, I'm Dennou Shojo Siro!
ときのそらです！
And I'm Tokino Sora!
あれ、これ私服ですね？
Oh, you're in casual clothes?
そうなんです。
That's right.
でもせっかくステージなので、何かやってくれたりしないんですか？
But since we're on stage, won't you do something?
じゃあ、じゃあ、やりまーす！
Then, then, we'll do it!
一緒にやりまーす！
We'll do it together!
はーい！
Yes!
というわけで、早速二人でこの曲を歌いたいと思います！
So, without further ado, we'd like to sing this song together!
イエーイ！
Yay!
いくよ、
Here we go,
せーの！
one, two!
おねがいダーリン！
Onegai Darling!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try asking me for something.
おねがいダーリン 作詞：ナナホシ管弦楽団 作曲：岩見 陸
Onegai Darling / Lyrics: Nanahoshi Orchestra / Composition: Iwami Riku
ダーリン、あなた、私の言うこと全然聞かない。
Darling, you don't listen to anything I say at all.
あれほどやめてって言ったタバコもお酒も毎日二箱三合の
I told you so many times to stop smoking and drinking, but you're at two packs and three measures every day,
中には一日たりとも欠かさず。
without skipping a single day.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になってもサンボしてあげないんだから！
Even if your liver gives out and you kick the bucket, I won't do anything for you!
ああ言えばこう言う、てこでも聞かないあなたのハートは真っ黒です！
No matter what I say, you talk back, your stubborn heart is pitch black!
言いたい言葉は言わないし
You don't say the words I want to hear.
行きたいところからやりたいことまで決めてるくせしてだんまり。
Even though you've decided everything from where you want to go to what you want to do, you stay silent.
何、そんなのバカみたいじゃない。
What, isn't that just stupid?
そうじゃない？じゃない、じゃない！
Isn't it? No, no, no!
じゃない！
No!
いつも思わせぶりな感じで
Always acting like you're interested.
察してほしい感じで
Acting like you want me to guess.
わざと口にしないのずるくない？
Isn't it mean to intentionally not say it?
バカじゃないの！？
Are you stupid!?
おねがいダーリン、見て聞いて。
Please, darling, look and listen.
欲しいのは形のないもの。
What I want is something intangible.
馬鹿にしないで、見て聞いて。
Don't make fun of me, look and listen.
覗いてよ、瞳の奥の方。
Look deep into my eyes.
真っ直ぐ見つめて。
Stare straight at me.
おねだりしてみてほしいの。
I want you to try asking me for something.
ダーリン、私、あなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ。
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あの時、あそこに連れてってくれたの、今ではすっかりシラフで。
That time you took me there, now you're completely sober.
デレてはツンして、若さゆえの過ちとか言ってるだけなんじゃないですか？
You act sweet then cold, aren't you just saying it's a mistake of youth?
チョケては誤魔化し、スパスパ機三、
You're joking and dodging... puff puff, kisan,
あなたのおかげで私のハートはボロボロです！
Thanks to you, my heart is in tatters!
釣れない時は釣れないし
When you're not in the mood, you're really not.
こっちがなかなか言い出さないからいつも私が舵取り。
Since you won't speak up, I'm always the one taking the lead.
何、そんなのバカみたいじゃない。
What, isn't that just stupid?
そうじゃない？じゃない、じゃない！
Isn't it? No, no, no!
じゃない！
No!
どこか足元見てる感じで
Acting like you're looking down on me.
値踏みされてる感じで
Acting like you're sizing me up.
何よそれ！？
What's that!?
正直、喜ばせ上手じゃない。
To be honest, you're not good at making me happy.
ああもう、めんどくさいことしてるから、めんどくさいことになるんだよ！
Ah, jeez, you're making things complicated, so of course they get complicated!
あの子のダーリン、見て聞いて。
That girl's darling, look and listen.
切なさは飾りじゃないのよ。
This sadness isn't just for show.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで
Don't look away, don't run away
暴いてよ 心の奥の方
Expose the depths of my heart
一瞬のことじゃない
It's not just for a moment
おねだりしてみてはくれないの？
Won't you try pleading with me?
言葉にできない臆病さは
This cowardice that I can't put into words
したたかなことではないのよ
Is not a calculated thing
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Don't be spoiled, say it out loud
もう ちゃんとこっち向いてったら
I said, look properly over here!
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, Darling, look and listen
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something without a form
よそ見しないで 見て聞いて
Don't look away, look and listen
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Peep into the depths of my eyes
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで
Taciturn Darling, don't sleep
暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Expose my true face
お願いダーリン そばにいて
Please, Darling, stay by my side
触らせて 心の奥の方
Let me touch the depths of your heart
まっすぐ見つめて
Gaze straight at me
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try pleading with me
お願いダーリン
Onegai Darling
まつりちゃーん！ありがとう！
Matsuri-chaaan! Thank you!
頑張ってねー！
Do your best!
またあとでねー！
See you later!
お願いダーリン歌っちゃいました！
I just sang 'Onegai Darling'!
そうなんですよ。またまつりちゃんとはあとでお話したいなと思ってるんですけど、
That's right. I'm planning to talk with Matsuri-chan again later, but...
ま、次のね、ゲストのことも喋りたいということで、
Well, I also want to talk about the next guest,
次のゲスト、呼んじゃおう！
So let's call her out!
この方です！
It's this person!
わああああー！
Waaaaah!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はーい！というわけで私が参りました！皆様こんにちは！
Hi! So, I've arrived! Hello, everyone!
イエーイ！ころねっち、ころねっちでーす！
Yay! It's Korone-chi, Korone-chi!
今日も元気いっぱいでーす！
I'm full of energy today too!
ころねっち来てくれてありがとう！
Korone-chi, thank you for coming!
いやいや全然。遠くからはるばるやってきました！
Not at all. I came all the way from far away!
遠くから、そうだよね。
From far away, that's right.
そうだよ、遠くから。
Yes, from far away.
遠くからはるばるありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming all this way.
いいえ、もう娘のためですから！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
No problem, it's for my daughter! Happy Birthday!
お母さん、お母さんじゃ。
Mom... my 'mom'.
何よ。ママよ。あなたのママ。
What? I'm your mama. Your mama.
ママ。もう、みんな可愛いでしょ、うちの娘。見て、この顔面！
Mama. Everyone, isn't my daughter cute? Look at this face!
今日のメイクもバッチリなんです！
Today's makeup is perfect too!
メイクバッチリなんだよ。
The makeup is perfect.
可愛いでしょ。さすが私が産んだ子。
Cute, right? As expected of the child I bore.
ころねママ。
Korone-mama.
実はさ、今日さ、大事なお披露目があって、それをね、ころねちゃんに見届けてほしくて、
Actually, there's an important reveal today, and I wanted Korone-chan to witness it.
わかった、それで呼んだのね！オッケーオッケー！
I see, so that's why you called me! Okay, okay!
なんで呼んだのかと思った。オッケー！
I wondered why I was called. Okay!
なんで、なんでー！？
Why, why!?
いいよ、見届けましょう！
Sure, let's witness it!
はい、というわけでね、早速...
Alright then, without further ado...
衣装チェンジスターーート！
Outfit change, sta-a-art!
おお！なんだってー！
Oh! You don't say!
ときのそらでーす！
It's Tokino Sora!
違う、私がときのそらです！
No, *I* am Tokino Sora!
イエーイ！可愛い！
Yay! So cute!
めっちゃ可愛いの、うちの娘。
My daughter is super cute.
みんな、スクショタイムだよ。可愛い！
Everyone, it's screenshot time. So cute!
あらやだ、可愛らしいわ。
Oh my, how lovely.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ただね、これはですね、まあパターン1と言いますか、
However, this is, well, let's call it Pattern 1...
はいはい。
Yes, yes.
まだね、全部ではないんです。ちょっとね、あの普通のスカートバージョンのほうの新衣装ということで、
It's not all of it yet. This is the new outfit, specifically the normal skirt version.
へぇー！そうなんだ！
Ooh! Is that so!
そうなんですよ。可愛いね。
That's right. Isn't it cute?
可愛いね、なんか真っ白で。
It's cute, all in pure white.
すごい素敵じゃん。
It's really wonderful.
一番最初にころねっちに見せたくてさ。
I wanted to show it to Korone-chi first.
なるほどねー！みんな聞いた！？私が一番初めに見ちゃった！
I see! Did everyone hear that!? I was the first one to see it!
やだあ、可愛い！
Oh my, so cute!
え、じゃあそんなそらちゃんのせっかくならさ、みんなもっと近くで見たいよね！
Well, then, since we have the chance, everyone wants to see Sora-chan up close, right!
ねー、見たい見たい。
Yeah, they want to see.
私はもっと近くで見たい！
I want to see up close!
ちょっとカメラマンさん、カメラ変わってもらっていいですか？
Excuse me, Mr. Cameraman, could you let me take the camera?
ころねっち！
Korone-chi!
ちょっと私が、私がカメラするわ。みんなうち消えるけど、まあいいよね、うちいなくても。
I'll do the camera work. I'll disappear from the shot, but that's fine, right?
ちょっと失礼しまーす。ああ、可愛い！見て、なんかセクシー！とても！
Excuse me. Ah, so cute! Look, she looks kinda sexy! Very!
あら可愛い！ちょっとローアングルでもよろしいでしょうか？
Oh, cute! May I take a low angle shot too?
ローアングル全体に写しまして、あらそらっちこっち見て！
Capturing the whole thing from a low angle... Sora-chi, look over here!
目線ください！あ、可愛い！ポーズください！
Give me a look! Ah, so cute! Give me a pose!
なんかダッチューノみたいな。
Like 'Dacchu-no' or something.
ダッチューノわかんない。やばい。
I don't know 'Dacchu-no'. Oh no.
世代を感じる。
I feel the generational gap.
じゃあなんかハート作ってみて。
Well then, try making a heart.
はーい。
Okay.
あら可愛い！ちょっと上からのアングルも写して。
Oh, cute! Let's get an angle from above too.
やだあ可愛い！
Oh my, so cute!
ちょっと腰にこう手を当てて、こんな感じで。
Try putting your hands on your hips, like this.
可愛いんだけど！見てみんな、めっちゃ可愛くない！？
She's so cute! Look everyone, isn't she super cute!?
めっちゃ可愛い、めっちゃ可愛いよ。
Super cute, she's super cute.
え、髪もさ、実はちょっとさ、
Eh, your hair too, actually...
髪もさ、実はちょっとさ、なんていうの？なんか編み込み？編み込みみたいになってるんだよ。
My hair too, actually, it's like... what do you call it? A braid? It's done like a braid.
見せて見せて！可愛い！見てください！
Show me, show me! Cute! Please look everyone!
はい、皆さん。
Alright, everyone.
ちょっとね、気合入れて髪型もね...
I've put a lot of effort into my hairstyle too...
ちょっと後ろも失礼しちゃっていい？
Can I show you the back too?
やだ素敵！
Oh, wonderful!
見てみんな！可愛い、うちの子！
Look everyone! So cute, my child!
ママ、こっち見て！ママの方見て！
Mama, look here! Look towards mama!
ああ可愛い！見て！可愛い！
Ah, so cute! Look! So cute!
みんな、みんなの方手振ってるよ、ほら。
Everyone, she's waving to you all, see.
可愛い！すごい可愛い。
Cute! So very cute.
あ、いいですね。
Ah, looking good.
可愛い。
Cute.
いいね。あ、ありがとうございます、カメラさん。
Nice. Ah, thank you, Mr. Cameraman.
すみません、カメラ奪っちゃって。
Sorry for taking over the camera.
めっちゃ可愛かったね。
She was so cute, wasn't she?
めちゃくちゃノリノリで撮影してくれるじゃん。
He's filming with so much enthusiasm.
いや、可愛いなと思って。
Well, I thought it was cute.
ありがと。ありがとうございます、すみませんカメラさん。
Thank you. Thank you, sorry Mr. Cameraman.
みんな、スクショたくさん撮ってくれたかな？
Did everyone take lots of screenshots?
撮った？みんな、スクショ撮り忘れてない？めっちゃ可愛かったんだから。
Did you? Everyone, you didn't forget to take screenshots? She was so cute.
「うちの娘可愛い」って書かれてる。あ、うちの娘？
Someone wrote "Our daughter is cute". Oh, our daughter?
みんなの娘になった、もしかして？
Did she become everyone's daughter, maybe?
いっしょに頑張ろうね、うちらママ共として。よろしくね、頑張ろう。
Let's work together as fellow mamas. Nice to meet you, let's do our best.
ママがいっぱいになっちゃった。
There are so many mamas now.
うちらの娘、可愛いよね今日。
Our daughter is cute today, isn't she?
やったー、なんかこうやってね、みんなに見てもらえて私も満足しちゃったな。
Yay! I'm so happy that everyone could see me like this.
あ、本当に？満足しちゃった？
Ah, really? You're satisfied?
じゃあ帰るわ。お疲れ。
Then I'm going home. Good job.
ちょっと待って！お疲れ様でしたー、じゃないから！
Wait a second! Don't "good job" me yet!
なんだよ。
What is it?
一緒に歌ってよ。
Sing with me.
歌いたいの？
You want to sing?
歌いたいよ。最初からそう言いなさいよ。
I want to sing. You should have said so from the start.
いや、めっちゃ緊張するんだけど。
No, I'm really nervous.
ちょっと裏話してもいい？
Can I share a little behind-the-scenes story?
今から歌う曲、ちょっと踊りがあるんですよ。
The song we're about to sing has a bit of dancing.
あのね、ずっと横でこうやって練習してんの。
You know, she's been practicing like this right next to me the whole time.
もう必死なんだ。
I'm desperate.
全然、全然わかんない。
I don't get it at all.
ずっとこうやってんの、ずっと。だからね、ナンチに教えてもらったんだっけ、数箇所。
She kept doing this, constantly. So, didn't Nanchi teach you a few parts?
そう、だからなんか、それ見てあげて。頑張っている娘をうちらで見よう。
Yes, so please watch that. Let's watch our daughter doing her best together.
絶対間違える、怖い。
I'm definitely going to mess up, I'm scared.
いや、大丈夫やって。参観日の気持ちでうちら来てるからさ。
No, it'll be fine. We're here with the feeling of a parent at a school visitation.
どういうこと？めっちゃ関西弁になったわ。
What do you mean? I've suddenly gone full Kansai-ben.
そう、参観日の気持ちで来てるから、みんなもその気持ちで見守ってやって。
Right, I'm here like it's a school visitation, so everyone, please watch over her with that same feeling.
私たまにチラチラ見ちゃうかも。
I might peek over at you occasionally.
いいよ全然。見ていいから、みんなパパとママにしてあげてや。
That's totally fine. You can look, and everyone, let's be her papas and mamas.
大丈夫やって、心配性やねんめっちゃ。
It'll be fine, you're just such a worrier.
ねー。でも緊張してるけど。まあ歌は大丈夫だと思うんだけど。
Yeah. I'm nervous, though. Well, I think the singing will be okay.
まあダンスがぐちゃぐちゃになったらごめん。
But if the dancing gets all messy, I'm sorry.
大丈夫、うちも忘れるとこあるし。
It's okay, I have parts I forget too.
あ、ほんと？
Oh, really?
あ、大丈夫、大丈夫。
Ah, it's fine, it's fine.
可愛ければ許してくれるから。
If you're cute, they'll forgive you.
あ、もうダメやなと思ったら、こうやっておけば大丈夫や。
If you think "Oh, I'm failing," just do this and it'll be fine.
頑張り、頑張ります。
I'll do... I'll do my best.
頑張る？オッケー。頑張るって、みんな応援してあげてな。
You'll do your best? Okay. She says she'll do her best, so everyone, please cheer for her.
はい、はい。じゃあ一緒に言おうね。
Yes, yes. Well then, let's say it together.
せーの！ハッピーシンセサイザ！
One, two! Happy Synthesizer!
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで 届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy synthesizer, I'll play a melody that will reach the depths of your heart.
儚く散った淡い片思い
That fleeting, faint unrequited love...
笑い話だね今となれば
It's just a funny story now.
見るものすべて輝いて見えた
Everything I saw seemed to sparkle;
あの日々が綺麗に笑ってるよ
Those days are smiling beautifully now.
我慢することだけ覚えなきゃいけないの？
Do I only have to learn how to endure?
大人になって頂戴ねならなくていいよ
"Please grow up"... I don't want to.
知らないことばかり知らないなんて言えなくて
Only things I don't know, yet I couldn't say I didn't know.
大変お似合いで嘘ついてごめんね
"It suits you perfectly"... sorry for lying.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで 届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy synthesizer, I'll play a melody that will reach the depths of your heart.
つまらない建前やヤなこと全部 消してあげるからこの音で
Boring pretenses and all the unpleasant things... I'll erase them for you with this sound.
何のとりえもない僕にただひとつ
There's only one thing I can do,
少しくだけでできること
Even though I have no special talents.
心躍らせる飾らない言葉
Simple words that make your heart dance,
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them through electronic sounds.
好きになること理屈なんかじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic;
落ち着けなんていらないんじゃない
Maybe "calm down" isn't necessary.
時代のせいと諦めたらそこまで
If you give up and blame the times, that's the end.
踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
You have to take a step, or nothing will start.
ごめんね夜遅く寝てたところだったでしょ？
Sorry it's late, were you sleeping?
驚いた私も駆け出そうとしてた
Surprised, I was about to run out too.
心の裏側をくすぐられているような
Like having the back of my heart tickled...
惹かれあう二人に幸せな音を
A happy sound for two people drawn to each other.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほら楽しくなるよ 涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy synthesizer, look, it's getting fun! I'll play a melody that wipes away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない別に
You don't have to act tough;
自分に正直になればいい
It's okay to just be honest with yourself.
何のとりえもない僕にただひとつ
There's only one thing I can do,
少しだけできること
Even though I have no special talents.
ちょっと照れるような単純な気持ち
Simple feelings that are a bit embarrassing,
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy synthesizer, deep into your chest
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you
つまらない「たてまえ」や ヤなこと全部
All those boring "outward appearances" and unpleasant things
消してあげるこの音で
I'll erase them with this sound
何の取り柄もない 僕にたった一つ
I, who have no redeeming qualities, have just one thing
少しだけだけど できること
Something I can do, even if just a little
心躍らせる 飾らない言葉
Heart-dancing, unadorned words
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるよ
Happy synthesizer, see, you'll start having fun
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that wipes away tears
強がらなくたって いいんじゃない？ 別に
Isn't it okay if you don't act tough? Really
自分に素直になればいい
You should just be honest with yourself
何の取り柄もない 僕にたった一つ
I, who have no redeeming qualities, have just one thing
少しだけだけど できること
Something I can do, even if just a little
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち
A simple feeling that's a bit embarrassing
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey it with electronic sounds
はあ！かわいい！
Hah! So cute!
緊張したー。
I was nervous.
なにそれ？
What is that?
そうなんす。
That's right.
これが、え、いろいろあるパターンの２パターン目！
This is, well, out of various patterns, the second pattern!
かわいい！
Cute!
なります。見て見て、ドレス。
It becomes. Look, look, the dress.
なにそのドレス！
What's with that dress!
かわいすぎる！
It's too cute!
かわいい？ありがとう。
Cute? Thank you.
あ、おおーってありがとうございます。
Ah, everyone saying "ooh", thank you very much.
めっちゃかわいい。
So cute.
見て見て、すごいくない？
Look, look, isn't it amazing?
お姫様みたいや。
Like a princess.
ありがとー。
Thank you~.
かわいい。
Cute.
ちょっとこれで２ショット撮ってもらおう。
Let's take a two-shot together.
２ショット。いいよ。
Two-shot. Okay.
いえーい！
Yeeeah!
かわいい！
So cute!
めっちゃかわいいんだけど！
It's so cute though!
んーありがとう。
N~ thank you.
私もね、このね、お衣装初めて見たとき、
I also, when I first saw this outfit,
え？こんなにかわいいの私が着ていいのかな？って思った。
I thought, "Eh? Is it okay for me to wear something this cute?"
あー、かわいすぎる！
Ah, too cute!
ね、シロちゃんもまだ見てくれてるかな？
Hey, is Shiro-chan still watching too?
シロちゃんいるから。
Shiro-chan is here.
シロちゃん！
Shiro-chan!
シロちゃーん！
シビオガ直ったー！
The signal is fixed!
あら！大丈夫？
Oh! Are you okay?
おかえり！
Welcome back!
大丈夫だった？
Was it okay?
おかえり！
Welcome back!
かわいかった！あらー！ありがとう。
It was cute! Oh! Thank you.
まず娘さんは、はい、はい、結婚でもされるのでしょうか？お美しい姿で！
First, is the daughter, yes, yes, getting married? In such a beautiful appearance!
いや、もううちの子は誰にも渡したくない。
No, I don't want to give my child to anyone.
や、やっぱり厄介な親。
As I thought, a troublesome parent.
もうテレビに、前の、お母様もきれ、きれいでしたね。
Already on TV, the previous... mother was also beau- beautiful, wasn't she.
え、ホント？あらそう、うれしいわ。
Eh, really? Oh is that so, I'm happy.
すごいきれいきれいだったよ。
It was really beautiful.
ちょっと５００歳のママまだまだ頑張ります。現役です。
The 500-year-old mama will keep working hard. Still active.
新人Vtuberとよく間違われます。
Often mistaken for a rookie Vtuber.
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
わからない！なんでなんだろうね。
I don't know! I wonder why.
新人、でもね、モンスターペアレントを阻止したんで。まだ大丈夫。
Rookie, but you know, I prevented the monster parent. So it's still okay.
あなた清らかなペアレントでいようね。
You should stay a pure parent.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
キヨペアです。キヨペア。
I'm a Kiyo-pea. Kiyo-pea.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます。清らかなペアレントです。
Thank you very much. A pure parent.
ホントに。もうなんか心は浄化されるし、
Really. My heart is purified, and
めっちゃダンス練習したの伝わったよ！
I can tell you practiced the dance a lot!
あ、ホントにね。あー。
Ah, really. Ah.
あーって思って。
I was like "Ah".
かわいいかったー、めっちゃ。
It was so cute.
ありがとー。
Thank you.
わーって思ってた。よしよし。
I was like "Waa". There there.
必死だったよー。
I was desperate!
踊れた？
Could you dance?
たぶん！
Probably!
ホントに？
Really?
踊れてたよ。みんな上手だったよね？
You were dancing. Everyone was good, right?
みんな素晴らしかったよね？
Everyone was wonderful, right?
みんな上手だった人、パチパチパチ！
Everyone who thought they were good, clap clap clap!
もうごまかしてたけど！
I was just faking it though!
上手だったよー。めちゃめちゃ。
You were good. So much.
ホントに。そらちゃん素晴らしかった。
Really. Sora-chan was wonderful.
お衣装で、お歌を、ショートバージョンでも歌ってましたが、
In that outfit, the song, even if it was a short version,
好きなポイントはどこですか？
what are your favorite points?
ショートの方？こっち？
The short one? This one?
こっちの衣装。
This outfit.
あー、やっぱりね、これね、座るとわかるんだけど。
Ah, as I thought, this, you can tell when I sit down.
ふわーって。
Fluffy~.
あらー！かわいい！
Oh! Cute!
ふわふわな感じ。
That fluffy feeling.
ここのなか、このお衣装で。
Inside here, in this outfit.
白鳥像みたいだ！
It's like a swan statue!
白鳥像みたい！
Like a swan statue!
このね、なかひらひらがいっぱいで、こうボリュームがいっぱいあって。
This, inside there are many frills and it has a lot of volume.
なんか、こう、なんていうんだろう。
Like, how should I say it.
白って地味な色だとは思うんだけど。
I think white is a plain color, but...
そんなことないよ。かわいいよ。
That's not true. It's cute.
でもそれが、この衣装の形で映える。
But it stands out in the shape of this outfit.
うんうん。確かに。
Yeah. Certainly.
かわいい。さすが。
Cute. As expected.
え、でも私さ、やっぱりさ、シロちゃんもさ、衣装、衣装！新しい衣装で。
Eh, but I, as I thought, Shiro-chan also, outfit, outfit! In the new outfit.
あら。かわいいよね。
Oh. It's cute, isn't it.
ねー。
Right.
なんて足を、素敵な御御足が出ておられること！
What legs... such wonderful legs are showing!
素敵。
Wonderful.
お母様ちょっとおかしい気がします。
Mother, I think you're a bit strange.
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
なんかハアハアしてます。
You're panting.
ローアングルで行きません？
Shall we go with a low angle?
ちょっと。あ、あのそらちゃんが今日主役なんで。
Wait. Ah, Sora-chan is today's protagonist.
じゃあ二人共ローアングル。もしよかったら、二人のローアングル。
Then both of you in low angle. If you like, both in low angle.
あー素敵！
Ah, wonderful!
あー素敵なこと！
Ah, how wonderful!
ちょっと私も混じらせていただいて。
Let me join in a bit too.
ローアングルで！
Low angle!
私もアイドルだぞ！
I'm an idol too!
そうだよ！みんなアイドルだぞ！
That's right! Everyone is an idol!
あら可愛い！
Oh, how cute!
あら可愛い私たち。
Oh, how cute we are.
可愛いーわ！みんな見て！可愛いでしょ。
We're cute! Everyone, look! We're cute, right?
みんなも混じる。みんなも混じる。
Everyone's mixing in. Everyone's mixing in.
みんなもここに霊圧ある感じで。
Everyone has this 'spiritual pressure' vibe here.
ひぇー！怖いな、霊圧。
Whoa! Scared of the spiritual pressure!
可愛い霊圧です！
It's a cute spiritual pressure!
素敵ね。
It's nice, isn't it?
でもこの3人も、VTuberとして活動してきてる3人かなって。
But these three have also been active as VTubers for a long time.
だからね、なんか2人とも来てくれるなんて奇跡だなって思ってて。
So, having both of you come here today feels like a miracle to me.
そうかな？こちらこそだよ。
Is that so? We feel the same way!
だってもう、頑張り続けてきた子が、ご褒美！
I mean, a child who has kept working hard gets a reward!
そう！喜ばせてあげたいんだよ。
Yeah! We want to make you happy!
甘やかしたいの！
We want to pamper you!
すごい…もう私がこんなに、甘やかされていいのかなってちょっと不安だよ。
Wow... is it really okay for me to be pampered this much? I'm a bit nervous.
あ、甘やかしたいからさ、囚われた宇宙人しよ。お手手繋いで。
Oh, we want to pamper you, so let's be 'captured aliens'. Hold hands.
何それ？オッケー。お手手繋いで。
What's that? Okay. Hold hands.
囚われたそらちゃん。
Captured Sora-chan.
こういうこと？囚われました！
Like this? I'm captured!
囚われたそら。
Captured Sora.
囚われましたー！囚われてるー！
I'm captured~! She's captured!
そらちゃん甘やかそ。そらちゃんの良いところは、
Pamper Sora-chan! Sora-chan's good points are...
顔面！見た目！性格！
Her face! Her looks! Her personality!
声！ボディ！
Her voice! Her body!
正解！ありがとう！
Correct! Thank you!
めっちゃ褒めちぎってくれるじゃん。
You're praising me so much!
本当にこうやって、歌も歌ってくれて、たくさんおしゃべりもしてくれて。
Really, having you sing and talk with me like this,
今私すごい幸せ者だなって思ってる。本当に！
I feel like such a lucky person right now. Really!
良かった。そらちゃん幸せ者。
I'm glad. Sora-chan is lucky.
みんなもすごい喜んでくれてて。そうだよ。
Everyone is also very happy! That's right.
みんなの力で、そらがここまで来れました。ありがとうございます！
With everyone's support, I was able to come this far. Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます！みんなのおかげです！本当に！
Thank you very much! It's all thanks to everyone! Really!
これからも毎秒労りながら育ててあげてください。
Please keep taking care of her every second from now on.
可愛い可愛いしてあげてください。ママからのお願いです。
Please love her more and more. This is a request from her moms.
2人の、2人のところもぜひ遊びに行ってね！優しさ！優しさだ！
Please come and visit their channels too! How kind! So kind!
私も、2人のところに遊びに行かせてね！
Let me go and visit your places too!
分かった！いいよ！いつでも来て！いつでも遊びに来て！
Sure! Of course! Come over anytime! Come visit anytime!
いつでも来てね！待ってるよ。
Come anytime! We're waiting for you.
私を遊びに行かせてねが言えて、もう私は大満足です。
I'm so satisfied that I could say 'let me visit'!
本当ですか？
Really?
そらちゃんはこのあともね、アイドルすると思うので。
Sora-chan will continue her idol activities after this.
エール送ります！頑張って、そらちゃん！ありがとう！
So we'll send our cheers! Good luck, Sora-chan! Thank you!
ねえねえ、せっかく来てくれたからさ、2人はさ、
みんなに言いたいこととか、なんか告知とかあったら言っちゃいなよ。
Since you came all this way, you two...
if you have anything to say or any announcements, go ahead.
私は告知は特にないので。
I don't have any specific announcements.
あの、まあ適当にTwitterでも見てください。ときのそらをよろしく！
So, just check my Twitter sometimes. Please support Tokino Sora!
お母さん！何？告知ないからね。
Mom! What? I don't have any!
分かりました！代弁しましょう！あ、じゃあ、代わりに…
I see! Then I'll announce it for you! Ah, wait! Instead of that...
電脳少女シロをよろしくお願いします！ありがとうございます！
Please support Dennou Shojo Siro! Thank you very much!
シロもアイドルを目指して、そらちゃんのように頑張っていくので。
Siro will also aim to be an idol and work hard like Sora-chan!
YouTubeや『みんゲメ』もよろしくお願いします！ねえ、『みんゲメ』行ってるんだよね。
Please support my YouTube and 'Maming' too! Maming! You're doing it, right?
おめでとう！ありがとうございます！なんてあったかいんだ。
Congratulations! Thank you! Everyone is so warm!
シロちゃん、いろんな新曲聴いてるよ！ありがとう！やったー！
Siro-chan, I've listened to various new songs of yours! Thank you! Yay!
テンション高いな、私たち。高いね。みんなも高いしな。
Our energy is so high! It is! Everyone's energy is high too.
びっくりだよ、もう。テンション高い方が楽しいじゃん。そうだよね。
I'm surprised! It's more fun when energy is high, right? That's true.
そのあともブイブイ頑張ってね。ブイブイ頑張るよ。応援してます！ありがとう！
Keep doing your best from now on! I'll do my best! We're supporting you! Thank you!
それでは、私たちは消えます！
Well then, we'll be disappearing now!
消える…？お暇します！お暇します！
Disappearing...? We'll be taking our leave! Taking our leave!
今日のゲスト、電脳少女シロちゃんと天神子兎音ちゃんでしたー！バイバイベー！
Today's guests, Dennou Shojo Siro-chan and Tenjin Kotone-chan! Bye-bye-be!
そらちゃん頑張って！ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Good luck, Sora-chan! Thank you! Bye-bye!
そして私も一緒に飲み物を飲みに行ってきまーす！
And I'm going to go get a drink too!
はい、というわけで。
Alright then.
今日もたくさんのゲストのみんなが来てくれて、本当にたくさんおしゃべりできて。
So many guests came today and we got to talk a lot.
とっても幸せな空間で。
It was such a happy space.
みんなもパチパチパチパチと温かいコメント、ありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you for your warm comments too!
本当に私は、いろんな人に恵まれてるなと思っておりますので。
I really feel like I'm blessed with so many people.
これからもね、後半あるので。後半戦、行っていこうと思います！
There's still the second half, so I'm going into the second half now!
さて、ということでね、次のゲストの人と一緒に歌っていきたいと思います。
Well then, I'd like to sing the next song with the next guest.
IRySちゃんと『ヒバナ』！
With IRyS-chan, 'Hibana'!
ヒバナ / 作詞・作曲 DECO*27
Hibana / Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
コンコン 優しくノックして
Knock-knock, knock gently
乗り込め 心の奪還戦
Board the hijacked heart line
妄想ばかりがフラッシュして
Only delusions are flashing
加速するパルス 答えはどこだろう
The accelerating pulse, where is the answer?
さあさ 弱音はミュートして
Come on, mute your complaints
くだらないことで躊躇して
Hesitating over trivial things
冗談ばかりね あはは
Always joking around, a-ha-ha
壊せない壁がキスを迫るでしょう
An unbreakable wall will force a kiss, right?
ああ 嫌 こんなわけ
Ah, no, not like this...
aiya aiya わかってくれるでしょう
Aiya, aiya, surely you understand.
その頭を撃ち抜いて
Shoot through that head of yours.
終わんない愛を抱いてたくないの
I don't want to hold onto an endless love.
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me feel more properly anxious.
いないいないばあでしてほしいの
I want you to play peek-a-boo with me.
もっとちゃんと応えてよ
Give me a better response.
nananana...
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, it's incomplete.
nananana...
NOを空振った愛の中で
In a love where 'NO' missed its mark.
トントン、これでお相子さ
Knock, knock, now we're even.
生まれない時に籠っちゃって
Shutting yourself away in a time that's never born.
完全主義はスモーキーに
Perfectionism turns smoky.
言及（ことば）す声に目眩とモノトーンに
Dizziness and monotone in the mentioning voice.
Don't stop, go in and get the ace
You'll be a face with gears that all feel the same
Now heart-be and force you to end this game
You better give up and throw your MP5 away
aiya こっちも選んで
Aiya, choose this way too.
aiya どっちも壊して
Aiya, break both of them.
心の根を引き抜いて
Pull out the roots of the heart.
不甲斐ない愛を愛してたくないの
I don't want to love a pathetic love.
もっとちゃんとデクしてよ
Treat me more like a puppet.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's surely more fun when you can't even laugh.
もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
Melt me more properly.
nananana...
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, it's incomplete.
nananana...
NOを空振った愛の中で
In a love where 'NO' missed its mark.
そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
IRySちゃんありがとう！
IRyS-chan, thank you!
出してくれて嬉しい
I'm so glad you could join me!
一緒に歌えて最高！
Singing together is the best!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
Love you so much!
aiya そんなわけないや
Aiya, it can't be like that.
aiya わかってくれるでしょう
Aiya, surely you understand.
その頭を撃ち抜いて
Shoot through that head of yours.
撃ち抜いて
Shoot through it.
終わんない愛を抱いてたくないの
I don't want to hold onto an endless love.
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me feel more properly anxious.
いないいないばあでしてほしいの
I want you to play peek-a-boo with me.
もっとちゃんと応えてよ
Give me a better response.
nananana...
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, it's incomplete.
nananana...
NOを空振った愛の中で
In a love where 'NO' missed its mark.
不甲斐ない愛を愛してたくないの
I don't want to love a pathetic love.
もっとちゃんとデクしてよ
Treat me more like a puppet.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's surely more fun when you can't even laugh.
もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
Melt me more properly.
nananana...
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, it's incomplete.
nananana...
NOを空振った愛の中で
In a love where 'NO' missed its mark.
nananana...
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, it's incomplete.
nananana...
NOを空振った愛の中で
In a love where 'NO' missed its mark.
AZKiちゃんと刹那ティックコード！
Satsunatic Code with AZKi-chan!
そらちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
SorAzuいくぞー！
Here we go, SorAzu!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
いつだって 未来のためばかり
Always focusing only on the future,
「今」という時間を費やすけれど
we spend the time that is 'now'.
今だけは 今だけを 感じ合うことができたら
But if for just now, we could feel only this moment together,
臆（おく）にして 立ちすくんだ 心がもう一度動き出すよ
my heart that stood frozen in fear will begin to move once more.
震え出しそうだ
It feels like it's about to tremble.
胸の痛みも 涙の訳も すべて
The pain in my chest, the reasons for my tears, everything—
強さに変えて
I'll turn it into strength.
飲み込んだ想い 仰いだ空に 飛ばせ
Let the swallowed thoughts fly into the sky I looked up at.
つながるメロディ 流れる星に 変わってく
The connecting melody turns into a shooting star.
君のために歌うよ 君に届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so that it may reach you.
輝きは 世界軸（じく）を越えて
The radiance transcends the world's axis.
確かにここで 重ね合えた 鼓動（コード）
The heartbeat (code) that surely overlapped right here.
触れ合う音が 光になって 降り注ぐ
The touching sounds become light and rain down.
この一瞬が 永遠へと
Let this moment lead to eternity.
煌めいては 色付いてゆく 君と描いた世界
The world I painted with you is sparkling and taking on color.
いつだって 朝はくるだなんて
They say the morning always comes,
来てほしくない 朝もあるけど
but there are mornings I don't want to arrive.
夜の闇 引き摺り このまま隠れられなくて
Dragging the darkness of the night, unable to hide as I am
静寂をかき消して 叫びたい声を歌に変えた
Drowning out the silence, I turned the voice that wants to shout into a song
いつもそこにある
It's always there
隔て阻む壁も壊して進め
Break down the walls that stand in the way and move forward
胸の奥にある
Deep in my heart
忘れたふりで誤魔化し切れない鼓動
A heartbeat I can't fully hide by pretending to forget
乗り越えてゆく
Overcoming it
絡まった思い 音に変えて飛ばせ
Turn entangled thoughts into sound and let them fly
生まれたメロディ 激しく鼓動奏で合う
The born melody, heartbeats playing together intensely
言葉だけじゃ足りない 歌じゃなくちゃ届かない
Words alone aren't enough, it won't reach without being a song
情熱が胸を熱くさせてく
Passion makes my heart burn hotter
確かにここで分かり合えた鼓動
A heartbeat that surely found understanding here
時の流れも逆らうように開かれる
Opening up as if defying the flow of time
何度だって歌うから
I'll sing it again and again
君の場所がいつも光に包み込まれるように
So that your place is always enveloped in light
全てが崩れ出しそうで
Everything seems about to crumble
どこにも歩き出せない時は
When I can't walk anywhere
送り続けるこの鼓動
I'll keep sending this heartbeat
聞こえる場所探し 踏み出すよ
Searching for a place where it can be heard, I step forward
遠くの星が呟くように光る
Distant stars shine as if whispering
いつも何かを伝えるように歌ってる
Always singing as if to convey something
飲み込んだ思い 仰いだ空に飛ばせ
Turn swallowed thoughts into the sky and let them fly
繋いだメロディ 流れる星に変わってゆく
The connected melody turns into a shooting star
君のために歌うよ 君に届くようにと
I sing for you, so that it reaches you
輝きは世界地図を越えてく
The brilliance crosses the world map
確かにここで重ね合えた鼓動
A heartbeat that surely overlapped here
触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
The sounds touching each other turn into light and pour down
この一瞬が永遠だと
This moment is eternity
煌めきは色付いてゆく 君と描いた世界
The sparkle adds color to the world I drew with you
君と描く音が飛び立つ
The sounds I draw with you take flight
セツナチックコードまで
Until the Sethnatic Code
イエーイ！
Yay!
AZKiちゃんありがとう！
Thank you, AZKi-chan!
そらちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
そして、そしてこの新衣装！
And, and this new outfit!
もうね、あのリハーサルの時から
Well, from the time of the rehearsal,
こうもうずっと、「可愛い、可愛い」って。
I was like "Cute, cute" all the time.
言ってた！実際言ってたね！
You were! You really were!
ずっと「可愛い可愛い」って言って。
I kept saying "Cute, cute."
ありがとう。ね、今日はね、なんで、
Thank you. Right, today, well,
新衣装のそらちゃんと、そして
to celebrate with Sora-chan in her new outfit, and
記念すべき今日をお祝いすることができて、
to be able to celebrate today, this memorable day,
めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
makes me so happy!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
イエーイ、そらあずでした！
Yay, that was SoraAz!
じゃあ、ここでは、やっぱり、
Well then, I guess here,
歌の3人で喋りますか！
we should talk as the singing trio!
アイリスちゃーん！
IRyS-chaaan!
そらちゃんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いや良かった、火花もめっちゃ良かった！
No, it was great, Hibana was also really great!
ありがとう！私ここにいていいのかな？
Thank you! Is it okay for me to be here?
こんな清楚で素敵なアイドル2人と一緒に、
With two such pure and wonderful idols,
こんな額縁が一緒にこの場所にいていいのかな？
is it okay for a picture frame like me to be here?
いいのかな？
Is it okay?
いいんだよ！
It's okay!
いいんだよ、可愛いよ！
It's okay, you're cute!
火花もめっちゃ良かった！
Hibana was also really great!
ね、かっこよかったし、2人のデュエットも神、あ神。
Right, it was cool, and your duet was God, ah God.
あ神。みんな神だから。
Ah, God. Because everyone is God.
みんな神だね！
Everyone is God!
みんな神だよ。
Everyone is God.
今日本当の神もいましたけどね。
Although there was a real god today too.
そらママ？リアル神がいた。
Sora-mama? A real god was here.
100歳の神もいましたね。
There was also a 100-year-old god.
いましたね！確かに。
There was! Truly.
そうなんですよ。今日はね、こうみんなで楽しく、
That's right. Today, well, I want us all to have fun,
でもかっこよく、みんなの良いところが、
but also look cool, and I hope all your good points
いっぱい出るようにと思って歌を歌いたいので。
come out a lot through these songs.
本当に今日は、そらちゃんの「好き」がね、
Truly today, it's a live filled with
たくさん詰まったライブだったなと思います。
many of Sora-chan's "likes."
みんなに「これ歌ってほしいな」っていうのを
I just really asked everyone
めちゃくちゃ、あの「これ歌って」って言っただけの。
things like "I want you to sing this."
あー、すごいすごい！選曲も
Ah, amazing, amazing! The song selection
そらちゃんの「好き」が詰まったライブでしたね！
was also a live filled with Sora-chan's "likes"!
はい！はい、じゃあここでね、もう後半なので。
Yes! Yes, well, since it's already the second half.
ちょっとね、皆さんにもちょっと。
I have something a little, for everyone too.
お！プレゼントというか。
Oh! Like a present.
お！なんですか！待ってましたよ！
Oh! What is it! We've been waiting!
お誕生日のまさかグッズを作りましたので、
I've made birthday merchandise, could it be,
ぜひ見ていただけたらと思います！
so I hope you'll take a look!
グッズタイム！
Goods time!
それがこちらです！
Here it is!
ときのそら誕生日記念2022
5月15日販売開始
Tokino Sora Birthday Celebration 2022
Sales start on May 15th
2022年、記念グッズは2種類です。
For 2022, there are two types of commemorative goods.
フルセットだと、B2タペストリー、こちらの柄ですね、とマスクとケースになってます。
The full set includes a B2 tapestry with this design, and a mask and case.
で、今回はね数は少なめなんですけども、フルセットでご購入いただいた方には、
This time the quantity is limited, but for those who purchase the full set,
あの、直筆サイン入りポストカード、そして特典ボイスをつけさせていただきたいなと思っております。
I'd like to include a hand-signed postcard and a bonus voice.
よろしくお願いしまーす。
Thank you very much.
えー、すごーい！めっちゃ可愛い！
Wow, amazing! So cute!
可愛いー！
Cute!
Meowthdayにぴったりだねー！
It's perfect for Meowthday!
そうそうそう、ありがとうございます！
Exactly, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
一個ずつのやつがあると思うので、それを見ていきたいと思います。こちらです！
I think there are individual images, so let's take a look. Here they are!
こちらが、タペストリー。おるだん先生の今回のあの配信のジャケットのものをタペストリーにしました。よろしくお願いします。
This is the tapestry. We made the illustration by Ordan-sensei for this stream's cover into a tapestry. Thank you.
可愛いー！
Cute!
めっちゃ猫耳！
Total cat ears!
可愛い、可愛い。お買い上げいただきありがとうございます。
Cute, cute. Thank you for buying.
そしてマスク＆ケース、こちらになってまして、えーシンプルなものにして、いつでも使えるようにと思って色を考えました。
And the mask & case are here. I thought about the colors to make it simple so it can be used anytime.
で、あの、ケースの方もシンプルなものにして、マスクケースとしてだけじゃなくて、普段、学校行く人とか会社行く人とかには、ペンケースとかとしても使ってもらえるんじゃないかな、みたいなものにしました。
And I made the case simple too, so it's not just a mask case; people going to school or work can probably use it as a pen case too.
日常からシンプルに使えるものと考えました。
I thought of it as something simple for everyday use.
幅広く使えるね！いいね、透明な感じになってるんだね。
It's versatile! Nice, it's kind of transparent.
透明な感じになってます。
It's transparent.
ガンガン使いましょう。使いましょう。
Let's use it a lot. Let's use it.
フルセットの方はタペストリーとマスク＆ケース、そしてですね、特典にポストカードと特典ボイスになってるんですが、
The full set includes the tapestry, mask & case, and then the bonuses are a postcard and a bonus voice.
そのポストカードの方、数量限定の方は全部直筆サインで書かせていただきます！
As for the postcard, the limited quantity ones will all be hand-signed by me!
おー、お早めに！
Oh, hurry up!
そうだね、お早めにね。
Right, get them early.
そしてですね、数量限定がなくなっちゃった後は、えーとは、何だっけ... 箔押し...
And then, after the limited quantity ones are gone, it's... what was it... foil-stamped...
箔押し！
Foil-stamped!
箔、箔押し... 読めるかな...
Foil, foil-stamped... can I read it...
箔押し複製サイン入りポストカードとなっております。よろしくお願いします！
It's a foil-stamped replica signed postcard. Thank you!
素晴らしい！よろしくお願いします。
Wonderful! Thank you.
そらちゃん、まだ他にも告知することあるんじゃないですか？お疲れ様だと思うんですけど。
Sora-chan, isn't there something else to announce? I know you must be tired.
頑張って、ラストスパート！
Do your best, the home stretch!
えへへ、照れちゃって、言っていいのかなみたいな。ファンクラブから？
Ehehe, I'm blushing, like, is it okay to say? From the fan club?
そうそうそう、はい。そこ、二人が乗っけてくれる、ありがとう。
Right, yes. There, you two are helping me out, thanks.
えーファンクラブを私もやってまして、そちらの方のキャンペーンもあるそうで、こちらです！
I also have a fan club, and it seems there's a campaign there too. Here it is!
5月31日の時点で会員になってくださってる方に、5周年イヤー記念として、ときのそらオリジナル記念硬貨（風メダル）。
For those who are members as of May 31st, as a 5th anniversary year commemoration, we'll give a Tokino Sora original commemorative coin (medal style).
おー、全員にプレゼントいたします！
Oh, we'll give it to everyone!
全員？！入会でもれなくってことで。お願いいたしまーす。
To everyone?! You get it just by joining. Please look forward to it.
すごいピカピカの金。コイン好きなんだよ、集めたい。
So shiny gold. I love coins, I want to collect them.
ずっと保存しておけるように、良いものにしました。
I made it something high quality so you can keep it forever.
コレクションできるやつ。一日中眺めれば、これは。
A collectible item. You could stare at it all day.
そしてファンクラブの方でもなんと、あのお誕生日記念特別放送があります！
And in the fan club, there's actually a special birthday commemorative broadcast!
さらに、そちらの方はですね、スペシャルセッションライブということで、エレメンツガーデンの近藤世真さん、都丸悠太さんと一緒にコラボさせていただきます！
Furthermore, that one is a special session live, and I'll be collaborating with Seima Kondo-san and Yuta Tomaru-san from Elements Garden!
おー、すごい！スペシャルセッションライブ！
Oh, amazing! Special session live!
歌ですか？
Is it singing?
歌もありますし、お喋りもしますので。
There's singing and talking too.
おー、入るしかない！
Oh, gotta join!
ファンクラブに入ってる方はぜひお楽しみに。
Those in the fan club, please look forward to it.
入っていただけたら嬉しいなと思っております。日付は、18日になっております。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be happy if you joined. The date is the 18th. Thank you.
今すぐ入らないとね。18日。そこまで時間ないですよ。
Gotta join right now. The 18th. Not much time left.
楽しみ！楽しみです！
Can't wait! I'm looking forward to it!
すごい二人が乗っけてくれたおかげで、いっぱい私が喋りそうになったのが抑えられました。
Thanks to you two helping me out, I managed to hold back from talking too much.
告知できた？告知できた。
Did I get the announcement out? I did.
ありがとうございます。もっと喋ろうと思ったら早く早くって言われた、とても助かりました。
Thank you. When I thought about talking more, they told me to hurry up, so it was very helpful.
でもまだそらちゃんは、まだあるよね。
But Sora-chan, there's still more, right?
そうですね、まだまだあります。最後までみんな楽しんでいってね。二人ともありがとう！
Yes, still more to come. Everyone, please enjoy until the end. Thank you both!
バイバーイ！頑張ってー！
Bye-bye! Good luck!
ありがとう。はい、というわけで、ライブもいよいよ最後の一曲なんですが、
Thank you. All right, so it's finally time for the last song of the live, but...
ここでもう一つ。最後の、なんか、サプライズというか、まだあるんですよ。なのでそれを見せていきたいと思います。
Here's one more thing. One last surprise, there's still more. So I want to show it to you.
マイク！
Microphone!
そしてヘッドホン！
And headphones!
そしてネンニュン！
And Nen-nyun!
あんきも！
Ankimo!
私本当に知らなかったんですよ、ルンルンがいるの。ルンルンなんかプレゼントしてもらっちゃいました。
I really didn't know Runrun was here. I was given Runrun as a present.
可愛い、可愛い。ということで、なんかいろいろ、あ、準備ができました。
Cute, cute. So, anyway, I'm all ready.
そんなアクセサリーもプレゼントしていただけて、これで全ての...
I was also gifted these accessories, and with this, all of...
お披露目となりますが、まだあるので帰らないでー！
the reveals are over, but there's still more, so don't go yet!
というわけで、最後の一曲に行こうと思います。
And so, I'm going to move on to the final song.
これが新曲となりますので、聴いていただけると嬉しいです。
This is a new song, so I'd be happy if you could listen to it.
それでは聴いてください。そらを越えて。
Now, please listen. "Beyond the Sky."
私待ってるよ... 待ってるよ... 待ってるよ... 待ってるよ...
I'm waiting... waiting... waiting... waiting...
WOW...
張りたてのキャンバスに
On a freshly stretched canvas
私はまだひとりぼっち
I'm still all alone
一歩目を踏み出して
Taking the first step
ここから始まったストーリー
The story that started from here
夢で見た景色は
The scenery I saw in my dreams was
（超満員大アリーナ）
(A sold-out large arena)
憧れを叶えて！
Make your longings come true!
（青空の向こうへ）
(To the other side of the blue sky)
私待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting, waiting
この広い舞台（そら）で
In this wide sky
あの日からキミがここへたどり着くのを
Since that day, waiting for you to arrive here
今歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ
I'm singing now, singing, singing, singing
夢の方目掛けて
Aiming towards the dream
きっとどうか届いて！
I hope it somehow reaches you!
WOW...
円卓は広がって
The round table expands
瞬く無数のアステル
Countless twinkling Astels
夢みたいな色で
In dream-like colors
まだまだ追いかけ続けて
Continuing to chase after it more and more
チャレンジはとまらない
The challenge doesn't stop
（継続的スローペースドリーマー）
(A persistent slow-paced dreamer)
点と点を繋げて
Connecting the dots
（星間線上へ）
(Onto the interstellar line)
私待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting, waiting
今もずっとここで
Even now, always here
いつの日かキミが見つけてくれますように
Hoping that someday you will find me
ねぇ歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ
Hey, I'm singing, singing, singing, singing
時空間を越えて
Crossing through time and space
キミのもとへ届いて！
Reach out to where you are!
WOW...
待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
Waiting, waiting, waiting, waiting
時代が変わっても
Even if times change
同じ星が彼方向こうへ飛び立とうとも
Even if the same star tries to fly far away
寂しくても何度でも 歓声を原動力に変えて
Turning the cheers into motivation again and again
ここまで歩んできた私なら...！
If it's me who has walked this far...!
私待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting, waiting
この広い舞台（そら）で
In this wide sky
あの日からキミがここへたどり着くのを
Since that day, waiting for you to arrive here
今歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ 歌ってるよ
I'm singing now, singing, singing, singing
目指したあの場所で
At that place we aimed for
きっとどうか届いて！ 届いて！
I hope it somehow reaches! Reaches!
夢をどうか叶えて！
Please make the dream come true!
WOW...
最後にここで皆さんに、お知らせがあります！
Finally, I have an announcement for everyone here!
なんとー！
What do you know!
7月20日、アルバム発売決定ーー！
On July 20th, an album release has been decided!
4thアルバム「Sign」、2022年7月20日発売です！
The 4th album "Sign" will be released on July 20th, 2022!
ということでよろしくお願いします！今日最後のサプライズだよ！
So, please look forward to it! It's the last surprise of today!
みんなー！ありがとうーー！
Everyone! Thank you!